<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: release | Toura Mulberry]]></title>
  <link href="http://mulberry.toura.com/blog/categories/release/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mulberry.toura.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-03T13:57:38-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://mulberry.toura.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Toura Dev]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing Mulberry 0.2: More Features for Easy Customization]]></title>
    <link href="http://mulberry.toura.com/blog/2011/11/29/mulberry-0.2/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-29T09:21:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mulberry.toura.com/blog/2011/11/29/mulberry-0.2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/download/">Mulberry 0.2</a> is out today, with several new features to make it
even easier to customize your apps:</p>

<ul>
<li>In Mulberry 0.1, you had to be very verbose when overriding the default
styles. As of 0.2, when an app is scaffolded, the default theme is copied
into the app, where it can be modified directly. To pull any upstream changes
to the built-in themes, we added <code>mulberry update_themes</code> to the CLI.</li>
<li>A new <code>toura.app.Phonegap.registerAPI</code> method lets you create your own
wrappers that make it easier to do development in a browser. <a href="http://mulberry.toura.com/blog/2011/11/16/browser-based-development/">Read more about browser-based development with Mulberry.</a></li>
<li>We beefed up <code>mulberry create component</code>; it now automatically
creates a stub .scss file for the component, and adds an @import statement to
your theme's <code>base.scss</code> file.</li>
<li>Now when you add pages to your sitemap, you can just run <code>mulberry scaffold</code>
inside your Mulberry project to create them all at once, rather than having
to remember which ones to create yourself. <a href="/docs/Command-Line-Interface.html">Read about all the command line options.</a></li>
<li>It's often necessary to repopulate a component or a piece of a component when
it gets new data or its state changes. Mulberry 0.2 introduces the <code>populate</code>
and <code>populateElement</code> methods on components to make this easier -- just pass
it a template and the data for the template, and it handles the rest. <a href="/docs/Creating-Custom-Components.html">Read
more about custom components.</a></li>
<li>Lots of people were asking us about how to create custom routes; it was
possible before, but it's easier in Mulberry 0.2: we added mulberry.route and
mulberry.routes for defining custom routes. <a href="/docs/Javascript-API.html">Read more about defining routes and other aspects of the JavaScript API.</a></li>
</ul>


<p>We also landed a few other features, several bug fixes, some improvements to
the command line, and lots of docs. Read the full release notes
<a href="/docs/0.2-Release-Notes.html">here</a>.</p>

<p>As always, you can find us on Twitter <a href="http://twitter.com/touradev">@touradev</a>,
visit us in the #touramulberry channel on irc.freenode.net, or drop us a note
at <a href="mailto:mulberry@toura.com">mulberry@toura.com</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
