<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: release | Toura Mulberry]]></title>
  <link href="http://mulberry.toura.com/blog/categories/release/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mulberry.toura.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-02-10T16:52:05-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://mulberry.toura.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Toura Dev]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing Mulberry 0.3: Even Easier Customization]]></title>
    <link href="http://mulberry.toura.com/blog/2012/01/11/mulberry-0.3/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-11T15:39:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mulberry.toura.com/blog/2012/01/11/mulberry-0.3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's a new year, and with that comes a new release of <a href="/download/">Mulberry</a>! As with the previous release, our goal is to make it easier to get started with Mulberry, and once you're up and running, we want to make it easier to customize your app. Some of the highlights:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Installer scripts for OSX and Windows (Ubuntu is on the way):</strong>
Getting started with Mulberry used to require downloading and installing a lot of other dependencies. While we haven't been able to <em>completely</em> automate this, we have made it a whole lot easier. Find the script for your OS in <a href="https://github.com/Toura/mulberry/tree/master/install"><code>/install/&lt;os&gt;/</code></a>, follow the instructions in the README, then run the installer script, and you'll be up and running.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Customizable default theme:</strong>
The "default" theme used to be difficult to customize. If you decided to use it you were basically stuck with a <em>lot</em> of gray. Now all the colors and fonts can now be changed from the <code>themes/default/_settings.scss</code> file, so you don't have to dig through alot of code or create a completely new theme just to change some colors. The icons are now customizable as well. Simply replace any of the images in <code>themes/default/icons</code> with whatever you want.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Templates are now "page_defs":</strong>
In 0.2, we had "templates" which were yaml files where you'd define the layout for a page in columns and rows. But these templates also had a lot of non-presentational information, which tended to be confusing. So we changed things so that page layout is handled in CSS (as it should be), and page_defs got a little simpler. We added a few Sass mixins to help with page layout. <a href="/docs/page-definitions.html">Read more about page_defs.</a></p></li>
<li><p><strong>New and Improved Code Generators:</strong>
It was already possible to create new routes, but now you can run <code>mulberry create route '/foo/:bar'</code> and it will generate the necessary code and add it to <code>routes.js</code>, which you can then customize. Running <code>mulberry create page_def</code> will now generate a boilerplate scss file and add <code>import</code> directive.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>In addition to all the new stuff, we've got a bug of bugfixes, improved development server stability, and more complete test coverage. For the full story, <a href="/docs/0.3-release-notes.html">read the full release notes</a>.</p>

<p>As always, follow us at <a href="http://twitter.com/touradev">@touradev</a> to keep up to date on the latest developments, or get help in the <a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/toura-mulberry">Google Group</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing Mulberry 0.2: More Features for Easy Customization]]></title>
    <link href="http://mulberry.toura.com/blog/2011/11/29/mulberry-0.2/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-29T09:21:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mulberry.toura.com/blog/2011/11/29/mulberry-0.2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/download/">Mulberry 0.2</a> is out today, with several new features to make it
even easier to customize your apps:</p>

<ul>
<li>In Mulberry 0.1, you had to be very verbose when overriding the default
styles. As of 0.2, when an app is scaffolded, the default theme is copied
into the app, where it can be modified directly. To pull any upstream changes
to the built-in themes, we added <code>mulberry update_themes</code> to the CLI.</li>
<li>A new <code>toura.app.Phonegap.registerAPI</code> method lets you create your own
wrappers that make it easier to do development in a browser. <a href="http://mulberry.toura.com/blog/2011/11/16/browser-based-development/">Read more about browser-based development with Mulberry.</a></li>
<li>We beefed up <code>mulberry create component</code>; it now automatically
creates a stub .scss file for the component, and adds an @import statement to
your theme's <code>base.scss</code> file.</li>
<li>Now when you add pages to your sitemap, you can just run <code>mulberry scaffold</code>
inside your Mulberry project to create them all at once, rather than having
to remember which ones to create yourself. <a href="/docs/Command-Line-Interface.html">Read about all the command line options.</a></li>
<li>It's often necessary to repopulate a component or a piece of a component when
it gets new data or its state changes. Mulberry 0.2 introduces the <code>populate</code>
and <code>populateElement</code> methods on components to make this easier -- just pass
it a template and the data for the template, and it handles the rest. <a href="/docs/Creating-Custom-Components.html">Read
more about custom components.</a></li>
<li>Lots of people were asking us about how to create custom routes; it was
possible before, but it's easier in Mulberry 0.2: we added mulberry.route and
mulberry.routes for defining custom routes. <a href="/docs/Javascript-API.html">Read more about defining routes and other aspects of the JavaScript API.</a></li>
</ul>


<p>We also landed a few other features, several bug fixes, some improvements to
the command line, and lots of docs. Read the full release notes
<a href="/docs/0.2-Release-Notes.html">here</a>.</p>

<p>As always, you can find us on Twitter <a href="http://twitter.com/touradev">@touradev</a>,
visit us in the #touramulberry channel on irc.freenode.net, or drop us a note
at <a href="mailto:mulberry@toura.com">mulberry@toura.com</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
